CALLIE GORMAN

UX DESIGNER

calliegorman.design

calliegorman4@gmail.com 201-638-4568



DESIGN SKILLS

User Research

Competitive Analysis

Usability Testing

Persona Creation

Sitemaps

User Stories/Flows

Sketching

Wireframing

Prototypina

Brandino

Visual Design

FRONTEND

HTML

CSS

Bootstrap

Javasciij

jQuery

Githuh

TOOLS

Skatch

Fiama

Invision

myBalsamiq

Draw.io

Illustrato

InDesign

Digital Marketer turned Designer

I am a UX Designer with 5+ years of experience marketing in the tech industry.

My education in psychology and past work as a digital marketer have given me an ability to conduct effective user research, and therefore allows me to create intuitive designs that can increase user engagement rates to meet business goals.

RECENT PROJECTS

Led the UX process, including design creation, competitive and user research, and usability testing for:

vicarious

view prototype | view case study

A mobile travel app that prompts users to provides brief updates on each day of travel for family and friends.

connected

view prototype | view case study

A cloud-based storage application that features an intuitive interface, collaboration options, and dashboard personalization.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Digital Strategist

Jan 2015 - Dec 2017

IBM Analytics, NYC | Remote

- Implemented A/B tests to drive higher engagement rates on web pages
- Worked closely with design and development teams to build web strategies for new products and marketing plays
- Led strategy for 10+ quarterly digital campaigns that contributed more than \$1M of yearly marketing created revenue

Digital Lead

Dec 2016 - May 2017

Tribeca Film Festival, NYC | Remote

Chosen to develop digital and social media strategy for IBM / Tribeca Film Festival partnership.

Project Manager

Jan 2015 - April 2016

IBM Outthink Tour, NYC | Remote

Selected as lead project manager on a premiere event series, managing 10 teammates for events that drove 2000 net new clients.

LEADERSHIP

IBM Marketing Mentor

Jan 2015 - May 2017

Chosen by managers to mentor five new employees during their onboarding.

EDUCATION

UX/UI Design Program, Bloc

Dec 2017 - July 2018

Intensive user-centered design program building real web and mobile app designs.

College of the Holy Cross

May 2012

BA, Psychology, Pre-Business